Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Commercial Recordings Collection AIA.031.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: 78 RPM Records, circa 1903-1959; 2734 sound discs
  - Side A: Harvey, Frederick, "So We'll Go No More A-Roving" [OEA.12805] Side B: Harvey, Frederick, "King Charles" [OEA.1289] (His Master's Voice B.9636) (Disk XA78 825)
  - Side A: Harvey, Morton, "Somewhere in Ireland" [77137] Side B: Wilson, George, "You Brought Ireland Right over to Me" [77201] (Columbia A2346) (Disk XA78 2028)
  - Side A: Harvey, Morton, "Turn Back the Universe" [One-sided]" (Emerson 785) Side B:, "Blank" [] ( ) (Disk XA78 2659)
  - Side A: Haskins, Matthew, "Hat Me Father Wore" [] Side B: Flanagan Brothers, "Highland Flings" [] (Banner 2138-B) (Disk XA78 2413)
  - Side A: Haskins, Matthew, "Turf Man from Ardee" [8435] Side B: Haskins, Matthew, "I Will If You Will" [8484] (Domino 273), 1929 (Disk XA78 1366)
  - Side A: Hayden Quartet, "I'se Gwine Back to Dixie" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Victor Drum, Fife and Bugle Corps, "My Maryland March" [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 16104) (Disk XA78 1236)
  - Side A: Hayden Quartet, "In the Sweet Bye and Bye" [] Side B: McClaskey, Harry, "Ninety and Nine" [] (Victor 16532-B) (Disk XA78 2431)
  - Side A: Hayden, Dorothy with Micky Carton's Orchestra, "Ireland's 32" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Micky Carton's Orchestra, "Jim Hayden Polka" [Matrix # not listed] (Copley 9-238) (Disk XA78 1370)
  - Side A: Haydn Quartet, "Put on Your Old Grey Bonnet" [] Side B: Van Brunt, Walter, "It's Hard to Kiss Your Sweetheart When the Last Kiss Means Good-Bye" [] (Victor 16377-B) (Disk XA78 2428)
  - Side A: Haydn Quartet, "Old Dog Tray" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Murray, Billy, "Hear Dem Bells" [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 16686) (Disk XA78 1367)
  - Side A: Haydn Quartet, "Kathleen Mavourneen " [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 1416) One-Sided (Disk XA78 1368)
  - Side A: Haydn Quartet, "Medley of Plantation Songs " [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 60046) One-Sided (Disk XA78 1369)
  - Side A: Haydn Quartet, "My Wild Irish Rose " [Matrix # not listed] (Oxford 8396) One-Sided (Disk XA78 2025)
  - Side A: Hayes, Andy, "When It's Moonlight in Mayo" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Hayes, Andy, "Kelly's" [Matrix # not listed] (Celtic CI-1012) (Disk XA78 848)
  - Hayes, Guss, "Until You're Home Again", 1984 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Side A: Hayes, Richard and Kitty Kallen with Jimmy Carroll's Orchestra, "Our Lady of Fatima" [3627] Side B: Hayes, Richard and Kitty Kallen with Jimmy Carroll's Orchestra, "Honestly I Love You" [3628] (Mercury 5466) (Disk XA78 849)
  - Side A: Hayman, Joe, "Cohen 'Phones the Gas Company" [65841] Side B: Hayman, Joe, "Cohen 'Phones About His Auto" [71865] (Columbia A 3772) (Disk XA78 2395)
  - Side A: Hayman, Joe, "Cohen Calls His Tailor on the 'Phone" [29770] Side B: Hayman, Joe, "Cohen at the Real Estate Office" [65567] (Columbia A2488) (Disk XA78 850)
  - Side A: Hayman, Joe, "Cohen on the Telephone" [28564] Side B: Dupres, Fred, "Happy Tho' Married" [39197] (Columbia A1516) (Disk XA78 1354)
  - Side A: Hayman, Joe, "Cohen Telephones from Brighton" [29617] Side B: Hayman, Joe, "Cohen Telephones the Health Department" [29685] (Columbia A2192) (Disk XA78 2080)
  - Side A: Haymes, Dick, "My Snowy Breasted Pearl" [L.4629] Side B: Haymes, Dick, "Blarney Roses" [L.4627] (Decca 24291) (Disk XA78 851)
  - Side A: Haymes, Dick, "HuShanda-bye " [L.4626] Side B: Haymes, Dick, "Ould Plaid Shawl" [L.2624] (Decca 24292) (Disk XA78 2086)
  - Side A: Haymes, Dick with Gordon Jenkins and His Orchestra, "How Are Things in Glocca Morra" [L.4339] Side B: Haymes, Dick with Gordon Jenkins and His Orchestra, "Twas Only an Irishman's Dream" [L.4340] (Decca 23830) (Disk XA78 2081)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "From the Irish Roads" [DRL.1965] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "From the Irish Roads" [DRL.1966] (London LB.968) (Disk XA78 852)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Cruise of the Castlebar" [OEL.6713] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Girls of Coleraine" [OEL.6714] (His Master's Voice I.M.661) (Disk XA78 1342)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Humour Is on Me Now" [OEL.6709] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "WHiskey in My Tea" [OEL.6712] (His Master's Voice I.M.618) (Disk XA78 1343)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Three Flowers" [OEL.6711] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Bright Silvery Light of the Moon" [OEL.6715] (His Master's Voice I.M.605) (Disk XA78 1344)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Ould Man of Killyburn Brae" [OEL.92] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Lovely Maid of Sligo" [OEL.93] (His Master's Voice I.M.527) (Disk XA78 1345)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Girls of Coleraine" [GB.3357] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Inniskilling Dragoon" [GB.5416] (Decca 12070) (Disk XA78 1346)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Flower of Maghera" [TB.1689] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Old Larne Fair" [TB.1690] (Rex 15057) (Disk XA78 1352)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Castle of Dromore" [DR.12709] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Trottin' to the Fair; Country Kildare Fragment" [DR.12708] (Rex 15038) (Disk XA78 1353)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Galway Shawl" [DR.12707] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Inniskilling Dragoon" [DR.12705] (Rex 15037) (Disk XA78 1355)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Little Brigit Flynn" [D.R.11812] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Down in Glasloch" [D.R.11812] (Rex 15016) (Disk XA78 1356)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Stone Outside Dan Murphy's Door" [DR.11809] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Johnny, I Hardly Knew Ye" [DR.11824] (Rex 15015) (Disk XA78 1357)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Charming Nellie Gray" [OEL.330] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Nellie Bly" [OEL.331] (His Master's Voice I.M.1011) (Disk XA78 1358)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Sweet Carnlough Bay" [OEL.328] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Mary of Clonmel" [OEL.329] (His Master's Voice I.M.1010) (Disk XA78 1359)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Galway Shawl" [OEL.326] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Nyape, Nyape" [OEL.327] (His Master's Voice I.M.1009) (Disk XA78 1360)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Nora Lee" [DR.11810] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Six Miles from Bangor to Donaghadee" [DR.11811] (Rex 15017), 1915 (Disk XA78 1978)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "My Lagan Love" [DR.12704] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Gartan Mother's Lullaby" [DR.12708] (Rex 15039) (Disk XA78 1979)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "My Lagan Love" [DR.12704] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Gartan Mother's Lullaby" [DR.12708] (Rex 15039) (Disk XA78 2052)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard, "Bonnie Wee Window" [GB.3360] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Bright Silvery Light of the Moon" [GB.3361] (Decca 12069) (Disk XA78 2087)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard and Anna Meakin, "Nell Flaherty's Drake" [OEL.140] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Tread on the Tail of Me Coat" [OEL.147] (His Master's Voice I.M.811) (Disk XA78 1361)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard and Anna Meakin, "Bonnie Wee Window" [OEL.137] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Stone Outside Dan Murphy's Door" [OEL.148] (His Master's Voice I.M.798) (Disk XA78 1362)
  - Side A: Hayward, Richard and Delia Murphy, "Lovely Sailor Boy" [OEL.6708] Side B: Hayward, Richard, "Banks of the Bann" [OEL.6716] (His Master's Voice I.M.668) (Disk XA78 1341)
  - Side A: Healy, Jack, "Ireland Over All" [64247] Side B: Healy, Jack, "Travelling" [64248] (Decca 12178) (Disk XA78 853)
  - Side A: Healy, Sean, "Eileen Oge" [OEA.6705] Side B: Healy, Sean, "Kerry Recruit" [OEA.6706] (His Master's Voice I.M.606) (Disk XA78 1351)
  - Side A: Heart of Paddy Whack, "Little Bit of Heaven" [3441] Side B: Heart of Paddy Whack, "Irish Eyes of Love" [3444] (Edison 50224) (Disk XA78 2088)
  - Side A: Heath, Ted, "Jungle Fantasy" [DR-12842] Side B: Heath, Ted, "Piper's Patrol" [DR-17142] (London 1259) (Disk XA78 1349)
  - Side A: Heath, Ted and His Music with Stanly Black and His Orchestra, "Scottish Rhapsody" [DR.16645] Side B: Heath, Ted and His Music with Stanly Black and His Orchestra, "Irish Fantasy" [DR.16646] (London 1185) (Disk XA78 1350)
  - Side A: Heidelberg Quintette with Will Oakland, "My Little Lovin' Sugar Babe" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Campbell and Burr, "Shamrock Belles" [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 17236) (Disk XA78 1405)
  - Side A: Heidt, Horace and His Brigadiers, "I'll Take You Home Again, Kathleen" [B.22343] Side B: Heidt, Horace and His Brigadiers, "TK" [B.22345] (Brunswick 8074) (Disk XA78 854)
  - Side A: Helena, Miss Edith, "Last Rose of Summer " [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 4010) One-Sided (Disk XA78 1348)
  - Side A: Helena, Miss Edith, "Last Rose of Summer " [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 5167) One-Sided (Disk XA78 1877)
  - Side A: Heller, Virginia, "Believe Me, If All Those Endearing Young Charms" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Heller, Virginia, "Home, Sweet Home" [Matrix # not listed] (Supertone S2107) (Disk XA78 1347)
  - Side A: Hempel, Frieda and The Old Home Singers, "Little Alabama Coon" [6223] Side B: Middleton, Arthur, "Father O'Flynn" [4770] (Edison 82562) (Disk XA78 1538)
  - Side A: Hemus, Percy, "Iris Love Song [One-sided]" [] Side B:, "" [] ( ) (Disk XA78 2419)
  - Side A: Henry Ford's Old Time Dance Orchestra, "Badger-Gavotte" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Henry Ford's Old Time Dance Orchestra, "Varsovienne" [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 19910), 1926 (Disk XA78 1293)
  - Side A: Henry Ford's Old Time Dance Orchestra, "Schottische" [Not Listed] Side B: Henry Ford's Old Time Dance Orchestra, "Ripple" [Not Listed] (Victor 19907-B) (Disk XA78 2354)
  - Side A: Herborn, Edward and James Wheeler, "Stack of Barley" [130838] Side B: Herborn, Edward and James Wheeler, "Rocky Road to Dublin" [130839] (Okeh 84113) (Disk XA78 622)
  - Side A: Herborn, Edward and James Wheeler, "Mouse in the Cupboard" [47242] Side B: Herborn, Edward and James Wheeler, "Miss Dalton's Reel" [47243] (Columbia A2182), 1916 (Disk XA78 1379)
  - Side A: Heywood, Eddie, "Peg O' My Heart" [73926] Side B: Heywood, Eddie, "Yesterdays" [73925] [47243] (Decca 23960) (Disk Xa78 2712)
  - Side A: Higgins, Charley, "John McKenna's Farewell" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Higgins, Charley, "Bucks from the Mountains" [Matrix # not listed] (Irish 13016) (Disk XA78 1392)
  - Side A: Hill, Murray K., "Father Was Out" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Porter, Steve, "Flanagan's Motor Car" [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 16436) (Disk XA78 1403)
  - Side A: Himber, Richard and his Ritz-Carlton Orchestra, "Me and the Moon" [] Side B: Himber, Richard and his Ritz-Carlton Orchestra, "Midnight Blue" [] (Victor 25365-B) (Disk XA78 2306)
  - Side A: Himber, Richard and his Ritz-Carlton Orchestra, "Would You?" [] Side B: Himber, Richard and his Ritz-Carlton Orchestra, "I've Got A Heavy Date" [] (Victor 25298-B) (Disk XA78 2313)
  - Side A: Himmerlreich, Ferdinand, "Believe Me If All Those Endearing Young Charms" [8774] Side B: Himmerlreich, Ferdinand, "Last Hope" [8773] (Edison 51285) (Disk XA78 623)
  - Side A: Hinkle, Miss Florence, "Believe Me if All Those Endearing Young Charms " [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 2953) One-Sided (Disk XA78 1883)
  - Side A: Hogan, Larry, "Reels" [CAL.226] Side B: Hogan, Larry, "Set Dance" [CAL.228] (Regal IZ.1044) (Disk XA78 1398)
  - Side A: Holliday, Michael, "With Me Ould Clay Pipe " [CA 24227] Side B: Holliday, Michael, "Darlin' Katie" [CA 24228] (Columbia IDB.728) (Disk XA78 1374)
  - Side A: Holt, Mrs. A. Stewart, "Winter Lullaby" [4193] Side B: Holt, Mrs. A. Stewart, "Rock Me to Sleep, Mother" [4320] (Columbia A809) (Disk XA78 2341)
  - Side A: Homer, Louise, "Hard Times, Come Again No More [One-sided]" [] Side B:, "" [] ( ) (Disk XA78 2410)
  - Side A: Homestead Trio, "Old Virginny Days" [5481] Side B: Van Brunt, Walter, "When I'm Gone You'll Soon Forget" [3563] (Edison 80411) (Disk XA78 2695)
  - Side A: Honeydreamers, "Irish Mambo" [AA-1011] Side B: Honeydreamers, "Five Minutes to Twelve" [AA-1012] (Double AA Record AA-105) (Disk XA78 1381)
  - Side A: Hooley, William F., "Kathleen Mavourneen " [Matrix # not listed] (Audiodisc D.V.15) One-Sided Non-commercial (Disk XA78 624)
  - Side A: Hooley, William F., "Wearing of the Green" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Glenn, Wilfred, "Off to Philadelphia" [Matrix # not listed] ( 17348) (Disk XA78 1406)
  - Side A: Hopper, De Wolf, "Casey at the Bat" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Bell, Digby, "Man Who Fanned Casey" [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 35290) 12 Inch (Disk XA78 2240)
  - Side A: Hosie, Hiram, "Hornpipe Medley" [M1010A] Side B: Hosie, Hiram, "Strathspey" [M1011B] (Beltona BL.2483) (Disk XA78 1371)
  - Side A: Hour of Charm Choir, "Our Lady Fatima" [EO-VB-5522] Side B: Hour of Charm Choir, "Ave Maria" [EO-VB 5523] (RCA Victor 20-3920) (Disk XA78 1397)
  - Side A: Houston, Bob, "Leprechaun Lullaby" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Houston, Bob, "Just a Kiss Apart" [Matrix # not listed] (MGM 10557) (Disk XA78 1394)
  - Side A: Hubbert, Uncle Steve and His Boys, "Two Step Quadrille" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Hubbert, Uncle Steve and His Boys, "Larry O'Gaff" [Matrix # not listed] (Gennett 6101) (Disk XA78 1898)
  - Side A: Hum and Strum, "Nobody Knows What Happened to McCarthy" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Hum and Strum, "If I Knock the 'L' out of Kelly" [Matrix # not listed] (Copley 9-148) (Disk XA78 625)
  - Side A: Hum and Strum, "Nobody Knows What Happened to McCarty" [2016] Side B: Hum and Strum, "If I Knock the 'L' out of Kelly" [2013] (Stellar SR 1002B) (Disk XA78 626)
  - Side A: Hum and Strum, "Bridget O'Flynn" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Hum and Strum, "Steve O'Donnell's Wake" [Matrix # not listed] (Stellar SR 1004) (Disk XA78 641)
  - Side A: Hum and Strum, "Irish Were Egyptians Long Ago" [2008] Side B: Hum and Strum, "Daughter of Rosie O'Grady" [2014] (Stellar SR 1005) (Disk XA78 1400)
  - Side A: Hum and Strum, "Steve O'Donnell's Wake" Side B: Hum and Strum, "Bridget O'Flynn", undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Side A: Hunting, Russell, "Casey Taking the Census" [20786B] Side B: Hunting, Russell, "Bureau" [20786A] (Perfect 11038) (Disk XA78 657)
  - Side A: Hunting, Russell, "Casey Courting His Girl" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Hunting, Russell, "Casey Selling Patent Medicine" [Matrix # not listed] (Pathé 20202) (Disk XA78 1395)
  - Side A: Hunting, Russell, "Casey at the Circus" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Hunting, Russell, "Casey Serenades His Girl" [Matrix # not listed] (Pathé 20327) (Disk XA78 1396)
  - Side A: Hunting, Russell - The Original Michael Casey, "Casey at the Wake" [A.93.885] Side B: Hunting, Russell - The Original Michael Casey, "Casey Home From the Front" [A.93.890] (Pathe 30308) 12 Inch (Disk XA78 2241)
  - Side A: Hyde Brothers, "Back o' the Haggart" [CO 37136] Side B: Hyde Brothers, "Blind Fiddlers" [CO 37151] (Columbia 33502-F) (Disk XA78 642)
  - Side A: Ian Powrie's Scottish Country Dance Band, "Mrs. Hepburn Belches of Invermay" [M.3249] Side B: Ian Powrie's Scottish Country Dance Band, "Dunoon Barn Dance" [M.3254] (Beltona BL.2602) (Disk XA78 570)
  - Side A: Innisfail Irish Orchestra, "Medley of Two-Steps" [W.111697] Side B: Innisfail Irish Orchestra, "Medley of Waltzes" [W.111699] (Regal Zonophone IZ.187), 1930 (Disk XA78 1399)
  - Side A: International Novelty Orchestra, "Orphan Waltz" [] Side B: International Novelty Orchestra, "International Polka" [] (Victor 78795-B) (Disk XA78 2433)
  - Side A: International Novelty Orchestra, "She Loves Me " [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Virginians, "Sious City Sue " [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 19439) (Disk XA78 643)
  - Side A: International Novelty Orchestra, "Barcelona" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: International Novelty Orchestra, "On the Riviera " [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 20113) (Disk XA78 644)
  - Side A: International Novelty Orchestra, "It Ain't Gonna Rain No Mo' " [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Dizzy Trio, "Hayseed Rag " [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 19421-B) (Disk XA78 2133)
  - Side A: Irish All Stars, "Irish Washerwoman" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Irish All Stars, "Miss McLeod's Reel" [Matrix # not listed] (Copley 9-170) (Disk XA78 645)
  - Side A: Irish All Stars, "Old Blackguard" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Irish All Stars, "Sailor's Hornpipe" [Matrix # not listed] (Copley 9-172) (Disk XA78 646)
  - Side A: Irish All Stars, "Chase Me Charlie" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Irish All Stars, "Mullingar Races" [Matrix # not listed] (Copley 9-173) (Disk XA78 647)
  - Side A: Irish Army Band No.1, "Wearing of the Green" [30-5692] Side B: Irish Army Band No.1, "Irish Army Bugle Calls" [30-5693] (His Master's Voice I.M.410) (Disk XA78 1383)
  - Side A: Irish Army Band No.1, "St. Patrick's Day March" [30-6123] Side B: Irish Army Band No.1, "General Mulcahy March" [30-6124] (His Master's Voice I.M.417) (Disk XA78 1384)
  - The Irish Balladeers, "Irish Rebel Songs", undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Side A: Irish Barn Dance Boys, "Green Meadows" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Irish Barn Dance Boys, "Cherish the Ladies" [Matrix # not listed] (Joe Davis 3600) (Disk XA78 648)
  - Irish National Orchestra and Choir, "The Best of Ireland's Music", undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Side A: Irish Pipers' Band of Boston, "Connaught Man's Ramble" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Irish Pipers' Band of Boston, "Father O'Flynn" [Matrix # not listed] (Bluebird B-4995) (Disk XA78 649)
  - The Irish Rebels, "The Rebel Songs of Ireland", undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "In Summertime on Bredon" [OEA.12972] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "To the Children" [OEA.12974] (His Master's Voice B.9673) (Disk XA78 650)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "She Moved Thro' the Fair" [OEA.12973] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "Garden Where the Praties Grow" [OEA.12975] (His Master's Voice B.9713) (Disk XA78 651)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Garden Where the Praties Grow" [OEA.4553] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "Molly Bawn" [OEA.4558] (His Master's Voice I.M.471) (Disk XA78 652)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Plank" [OEA.4554] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "Palatine's Daughter" [OEA.4559] (His Master's Voice I.P.317) (Disk XA78 653)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Palatine's Daughter" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "Molly Bawn" [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 25590) (Disk XA78 654)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Road to the Isles" [OEA.8537] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "Sea Fever" [OEA.8540] (His Master's Voice B.9073) (Disk XA78 1385)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Vagabond" [OEA.10758] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "Bright Is the Ring of Words" [OEA.10759] (His Master's Voice B.9504) (Disk XA78 1386)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Lord Lovell" [OEA.11781] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "In Newlyn Town" [OEA.11782] (His Master's Voice B.9856) (Disk XA78 1387)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Oyster Girl" [OEA.11273] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "One Eyed Riley" [OEA.11272] (His Master's Voice I.P.419) (Disk XA78 1388)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Pleasant and Delightful" [OEA.11270] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "Wild Rover" [OEA.11271] (His Master's Voice I.P.420) (Disk XA78 1389)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Roadside Fire" [OEA.10760] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "Linden Lea" [OEA.10761] (His Master's Voice I.P.429) (Disk XA78 1390)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Little Mary Cassidy" [OEA.4552] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "She is Far from the Land" [OEA.4557] (His Master's Voice I.M.469) (Disk XA78 2101)
  - Side A: Irwin, Robert, "Fairy Tales of Ireland" [OEA.6077] Side B: Irwin, Robert, "Hills of Donegal" [OEA.6079] (His Master's Voice I.M.489) (Disk XA78 2102)
  - Ives, Burl, "Songs of Ireland", undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Side A: Ives, Burl, "Wayfaring Stranger" [CO 29846] Side B: Ives, Burl, "Wayfaring Stranger" [CO 29676] (Columbia 36734) (Disk XA78 1375)
  - Side A: J.L. Hudson Company Male Quartet, "Phantom Band" [E.67198-1] Side B: J.L. Hudson Company Male Quartet, "Milligan Musketeers" [E.67199-1] (Pathe 29229) 12 Inch (Disk XA78 2242)
  - Side A: Jack Barrett's Boyne Quartet, "Priest in His Boots" [OEP.283] Side B: Jack Barrett's Boyne Quartet, "Bonnie Kate" [OEP.284] (Glenside W.182) (Disk XA78 970)
  - Side A: Jack Barrett's Boyne Quartet, "Reels" [OEP.280] Side B: Jack Barrett's Boyne Quartet, "HornPipes" [OEP.285] (Glenside W.181) (Disk XA78 971)
  - Side A: Jacques Orchestra, "Sad Story" [OEA.14418] Side B: Jacques Orchestra, "Anes" [OEA.14419] (His Master's Voice B.9942) (Disk XA78 1391)
  - Side A: Jacques Orchestra, "Greensleeves - Fantasia" [CAX.8523] Side B: Jacques Orchestra, "Keltic Lament" [CAX.8524] (Columbia DX.925) 12 Inch (Disk XA78 2243)
  - Side A: James Morrison's Trio, "Cup of Tea – Peter Street" [18569] Side B: Morrison, James, "Maurice Carmody Favorite" [18572] (Okeh 84179) (Disk XA78 494)
  - Side A: James, Harry, "Ciribiribin" [BW 24514] Side B: James, Harry, "Sweet Georgia Brown" [BW 24515] (Brunswick 8327) (Disk XA78 1372)
  - Side A: James, Harry, "Flatbush Flanagan" [CO 29422] Side B: James, Harry, "I'll Get By" [CO 30195] (Columbia 36698) (Disk XA78 2323)
  - Side A: James, Harry and His Orchestra, "Flight of the Bumble Bee" [CO 29726] Side B: James, Harry and His Orchestra, "Flatbush Flanagan" [CO 29422] (Columbia M 186) (Disk XA78 656)
  - Side A: James, Lewis, "Tired of Me" [79079] Side B: James, Lewis, "Rose of Washington Square" [79084] (Columbia A2928) (Disk XA78 1376)
  - Side A: James, Lewis, "Don't Cry Frenchy, Don't Cry" [78282] Side B: Burr, Henry, "After All" [78290] (Columbia A2704) (Disk XA78 1377)
  - Side A: James, Lewis, "Last Little Mile Is the Longest " [7873] Side B: Jones, Billy, "Peggy O'Neil" [Matrix # not listed] (Edison 50792) (Disk XA78 1382)
  - Side A: James, Lewis, "Smile and the World Smiles with You " [Matrix # not listed] Side B: James, Lewis, "That Tumble-down Shack in Athlone" [Matrix # not listed] (Victor 18545), 1919 (Disk XA78 1991)
  - Side A: Jans, Harry and Harold Wheelen, "Well, the Irish and the Germans Got Together" [43566] Side B: Miller, Jim and Charlie Farrell, "Let's Give Three Cheers" [43567] (Victor 21367) (Disk XA78 1402)
  - Side A: Jardon, Dorothy, "Ballynure Ballad [One-sided]" [] Side B:, "" [] ( ) (Disk XA78 2446)
  - Side A: Jaudas' Society Orchestra, "My Bird of Paradise" [4152] Side B: Sisty and Seitz's Banjo, "Auntie Skinner's Chicken Dinner" [4166] (Edison Catalog # not listed) (Disk XA78 2132)
  - Side A: Jenkins, Gordon, "December" [75166] Side B: Jenkins, Gordon, "Happy New Year" [75167] (Decca 24767) (Disk XA78 1380)
  - Side A: Jenkins, Jess, "Sidewalks of New York" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Jenkins, Jess, "Red Wing" [Matrix # not listed] (Challenge 408) (Disk XA78 1373)
  - Side A: Jerome, Henry, "Auld Lang Syne" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Jerome, Henry, "Show Me the Way to Go Home" [Matrix # not listed] (London 860) (Disk XA78 1393)
  - Side A: Jerry and May Picking's Orchestra, "Hartford Fling; Molly Brannigan" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Jerry and May Picking's Orchestra, "Black Thorn Stick; Back of the Haggard" [Matrix # not listed] (Irish I 3015A) (Disk XA78 328)
  - Side A: Jerry Murad's Harmonicats, "My Wild Irish Rose" [UR-8540] Side B: Jerry Murad's Harmonicats, "Valse Bluette" [UR-8541] (Universal U-25) (Disk XA78 282)
  - Side A: Jerry Murad's Harmonicats, "Peg O' My Heart" [DLG.50017] Side B: Jerry Murad's Harmonicats, "Fantastie Imprompu – Op.86" [DLG.50018] (London 512) (Disk XA78 1575)
  - Side A: Jerry's Hayshakers, "Winnipeg Reel and Raggedy Ann" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Jerry's Hayshakers, "Road to the Isles" [Matrix # not listed] (Copley 8-509) (Disk XA78 683)
  - Side A: Jerry's Hayshakers, "Balkan Hills" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Jerry's Hayshakers, "Hundred Pipers" [Matrix # not listed] (Copley 8-514) (Disk XA78 684)
  - Side A: Jerry's Hayshakers, "Patronella" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Jerry's Hayshakers, "Silvery Bells" [Matrix # not listed] (Copley 8-515) (Disk XA78 685)
  - Side A: Jerry's Hayshakers, "Circle Hall Breakdown" [Matrix # not listed] Side B: Jerry's Hayshakers, "High Level Hornpipe" [Matrix # not listed] (Copley 8-516) (Disk XA78 686)